Jee Yoon Lee

An adaptable, creative technologist who applies design thinking reflective of technological and cultural transformations to real-world solutions. Collaborates with experts across disciplines to

build feasible and informed ideas into prototypes. Research focuses on distributed ledger technology and sustainable consumer packaged goods.

jee-yoon.lee20@imperial.ac.uk eeeeoo.com

+447 949 239044

Experience

KlimateLinK

Product Manager | Oct 2022 to Present

Synthesize product strategy and roadmap, based on input from engineers, users, partners, and competitive analysis. Develop scoping documentation, coordinate bug and UI/UX improvements. Identify ways to improve the app and onboarding experience to ease the adoption of web3 features. Familiar with Stellar blockchain and product management tools (e.g., JIRA, Notion, Figma, Firebase).

80minus

Co-Founder | Sep 2021 to Jun 2022

Developed a user-friendly, cost-effective, and efficient mercury detection device to trace mercury data in seafood. Collaborated with local fishmongers, global seafood companies, blockchain company, and other prominent government agencies to turn concepts into reality. Participated in Imperial College Enterprise Lab as top 25 teams out of 185 teams.

VizionHair

Creative Strategist | Sep 2021 to Jan 2022

Supporting John Vial to develop and launch a new premium hair-care beauty product line that will include digital tokens linking its ingredients to their natural sources. Consumers could track the conservation effort from their purchases. The products will be retailed at boutique retailers such as Harrods and online stores next year.

Bitek Technology

Product Design Consultant | Jun 2020 to Aug 2021

Helped shape product strategy in collaboration with cross-functional partners, including suppliers, engineering and product managers in the digital label printing industry. Worked with engineering and product managers on a new Raster Image Processor or workflowsoftware, delivering high-fidelity UI/UX designs and demoing progress to stakeholders.

MIT Media Lab. Personal Robots

Undergraduate Design Researcher | Sep 2018 to May 2019

Developed interactive survey for Android & iOS tablets to collect quantitative and qualitative data on robots using React Native and Ruby in Rails. Performed user studies with eldercare clients to evaluate participants' interactions and design needs with social robots, including Jibo.

Hewlett Packard Enterprise Korea

Digital Marketing Intern | Jun 2017 to Jul 2017

Coordinated marketing campaigns by collaborating with an in-house creative agency. Conducted CTA marketing for the Korean version of HPE's website, creating landing pages and driving traffic to the newly launched product. Translated product content and suggested conversion strategies to improve user experience.

Education

Imperial College London Royal College of Art

LND, UK | 2020 - 2022

MSc/MA Innovation Design Engineering (Merit)

Sustainable Systems, Innovation Strategy, Design Thinking, Creative Collaboration, Physical Computing, Human Centered Design, Industrial Design, Experimental Design Wellesley College

MA, USA | 2015 – 2019 BA Media Arts & Sciences (Cum Laude) 3.7/4.0 GPA

Massachusetts Institute of Technology Cross Registration, Design

Human Computer Interaction, Data Structures, Front-end Web Dev, Tangible User Interfaces, Art History, Creative Computing, Advanced Screen Printing, Video Production

Achievements

Imperial Enterprise Lab Venture Capitalist Challenge Semi-Finalists 2022

Blockchain Council Certified Blockchain Expert 2022

OPPO x Royal College of Art Winner 2021

19th London Design Festival 2021

Babson x Olin x Wellesley College The Weissman Foundry Fellowship 2019

Flatiron School Women Take Tech Scholarship 2018 Wellesley College New Media Scholarship 2018

Anderson Ranch Arts Center Scholarship 2018

HSK(Hanyu Shuiping Kaoshi) Chinese Profiency Test Level 4

Skills

Stakeholder Engagement

Collaborating with internal project partners and external stakeholders (e.g., academia, industry experts, and others) to develop, test, and refine a framework. Designing and planning sessions to help others achieve the most when working with technical concepts. Excellent public speaking skills and ability to present to top-level executives.

Research & Analysis

Conduct research on key business and policy issues related to the intersection of supply chains, circular economy, consumer culture in FMCGs, and climate. Break down the challenges and opportunities that complex concepts present in different scales by drawing on disciplinary and interdisciplinary research.

Development

In-depth knowledge of DLT concepts, including NFTs, DAOs, and blockchain for supply chains (e.g., DIDs, digital twin). Experience in front and back-end development (e.g., HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Git, React JS, Python, Ruby, SQL) and delivering presentations to technical audiences. Enjoy creative coding in processing is and Arduino. Pick up new platforms/technologies.

UX/UI Design

Worked with design systems at scale, across the web and mobile platforms, including Sketch, Adobe Creative Suite, and Figma. Produced exquisite visual designs driven by strategic UI thinking through iterative design process. Established high-fidelity prototypes that were informed by user research and validated with stakeholders and users.